

CONTACT ME AT

Email shingiebhengesa@gmail.com

Portfolio https://shingiraibhengesa.000webhostapp.com/

<u>Github</u> <u>https://github.com/ShingiraiBhengesa</u>

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Javascript
- PHP
- React
- HTML & CSS
- SASS
- Boostrap
- Wordpress
- Git & Github
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Invision
- Canva

COURSES

- Full Stack Web and
 Multiplatform Mobile App
 Development Specialization,
 The Hong Kong University of
 Technology, Cousera
- Machine Learning
 Foundations: A Case Study
 Approach, University of
 Washington, Cousera
- Digital Marketing Using Social Media, SEO and Google Ad Words, Udemy

SHINGIRAI BHENGESA

WEB DEVELOPER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a web developer focused on crafting great web experiences. Skilled in developing, designing, conceptualizing and deploying responsive interactive websites and great web applications. Experienced in maintaining websites and web applications, including content updates, account administration, debugging, feature enhancements and documentations, testing, and regular upgrades to ensure web security and system usability.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web Developer & Designer

Frontdreams Web Design Agency | September 2021- Present

- Designing engaging and responsive landing pages with html, CSS JavaScript, Bootstrap, WordPress and Joomla
- Integrating client CMS programs and data feeds into websites
- Optimizing sites for maximum speed and scalability
- Employing industry and design best practice through website build process
- Conducting website testing
- Liaising with back-end developers to ensure web and app logic is properly integrated
- Ensuring website function and stability across devices i.e., desktop, mobile, tablet
- Working with marketing and research teams to incorporate brand elements and relevant market research findings into website
- Providing internal support and external customer service throughout the build and launch process of the website

Contract Frontend Web Developer & Graphic Designer

Credz Online | May 2021 - August 2021

- Customizing WordPress themes and site maintenance
- Introduced new plug-ins and extensions to make the website more usable and interactive.
- Design, coordinate, and troubleshoot integrations, components, and infrastructures to run enterprise class website
- Monitor uptime, hosting, and databases to ensure site is performing at maximum capacity
- Designing company logo and graphics

Freelance Web Developer

Upwork | Jan 2018 - May 2021

- Designed and developed an interactive and responsive dynamic and static websites for small and big businesses.
- Developed interactive administration panels companies can use to control, manage and update web contents.
- Developed and designed ecommerce stores and ecommerce management systems.
- Integrated stripes for payments and implemented the checkout process in addition to developing reports for orders.
- Integrated 3rd party API's for modules pertaining to payment and email solutions.
- Edited Word Press themes and developed word press plugins

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Near East Universty

Bsc in Civil Engineering | Sept 2021